CHRIS MENDES Contract Front-end Web Developer

Croydon, South London **RESIDENCE:** NATIONALITY: British

inbox@chrismendes.london EMAIL: LOOKING FOR: Contract/Freelance roles only

I'm an experienced Front-end Web Developer with over 8 years commercial experience.

My website – chrismendes.london – built especially for recruitment agents and prospective employers, has a detailed account of my technical expertise as well as a comprehensive portfolio, code samples, and other useful information. I invite you to visit.

SKILLSET

KEY SKILLS:

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass/LESS, JavaScript
- AngularJS, Backbone.js, Flight.js, jQuery
- Twitter Bootstrap, Foundation, Susy
- Git, Gulp, Grunt

KEY KNOWLEDGE:

- Building web applications from scratch
- Responsive web development
- Object-oriented, modular, scalable code
- Web performance and optimisation

EMPLOYMENT

NOTE: My last employment contract ended December 2015. A frequently asked question has been the reason for the "gap" between then and now. During the period of February and June I was heavily involved in campaign activity towards the recent EU referendum. This of course has now come to an end and so after a short break now is the right time to return to the job market.

May 2015 - Dec 2015 Senior Front-end Web Developer <u>Surfdome</u>

(6 month+ contract) Wembley, London

Recruited to assist in the formation and execution of the technical management team's plan to advance the front-end technology behind the Surfdome.com ecommerce website.

Specifically responsible for re-writing the existing code base to a more modular and scalable state with modern libraries and well designed architecture, to improve and supervise existing code standards and workflow practices, and to help the development team to grow on this basis going forward.

- Designing and recommending a completely new front-end strategy and code architecture for the given functional and non-functional requirements
- Prototyping with modern libraries such as Twitter's Flight.js to create mini-apps replicating legacy site functionality for proof of concept purposes
- Introducing new front-end developer workflow and asset management procedures, substituting zero front-end automation and server-side Rails asset pipeline with Node.js and Gulp
- Establishing previously absent formal code style guidelines, as well as the practical means to enforce them, and authoring long-term developer team documentation
- Assist with the hiring process and co-conduct interviews to objectively identify the suitability or not of a given candidate

Dec 2014 - Feb 2015 **AKQA** Front-end Web Developer

(2 month+ contract) Farringdon, London

AKQA, one of the world's largest and most successful digital agencies, were set to deliver a new website for one of their UK clients - Barclaycard - to help launch a new consumer product.

Hired as part of a two man development team to build the front-end of the new site, together we worked within a wider team of AKQA creative designers, UX designers, copywriters, QA testers, project manager and a technical delivery manager.

May 2014 – Oct 2014 <u>Capablue</u> Front-end Web Developer

(3 month+ contract) Waterloo, London

At this highly innovative company - owned by Arqiva, a leading communications infrastructure company - I was drafted in to develop a white-label product for a new multi-channel live TV streaming web application accessible on desktops, tablets, and mobile devices (similar concept to BBC iPlayer).

Subsequently, I was asked to build from scratch a completely new version of Capablue's own company website. Working with a Freelance Designer, a Junior Developer, QA Testers, Project Manager, and Marketing Manager, I led the development and together we successfully delivered the new website.

Mar 2012 – May 2014 DNX Marketing Web Developer (Permanent) Guildford, Surrey

Working at this multi award winning agency (B2B Agency of the Year 2012 and 2013), my job was to collaborate with project teams that consist of account managers, designers, copywriters, and project managers, and build the agreed creative solution within the set time-frame and budget.

This predominantly involved building responsive websites with varying and wide-ranging client-side and server-side requirements, but also although less often, HTML emails, animated banners, and games.

Key responsibilities:

- Coding the responsive front-end of new websites with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/jQuery, and the Twitter Bootstrap
 framework, and back-end of new websites with PHP, MySQL, using the Codelgniter MVC framework
- Meeting with account managers and project managers to be briefed on new projects, and liaising with designers and other developers to propose, discuss, and agree on the envisaged end product and its technical makeup
- Supporting other developers with technical input and general guidance
- Running team meetings once every week, submitting meeting agendas, facilitating discussion and agreement,
 recording and sharing minutes, pursuing action a responsibility delegated to me by the department manager

Mar 2010 – Mar 2012 Fingo Marketing Web Developer

(Permanent) Epsom, Surrey

My role at this marketing agency primarily was to build new websites based on the visual designs produced by the creative team. As the leading developer I worked to one extent or another on the majority of all projects collaborating closely with the company directors, web designers, and the project manager from kick-off to completion.

- Creating fresh new websites ranging from static brochure sites, to CMS driven sites and more bespoke sites
- Providing technical input to support project requirements gathering and internal processes
- Liaising with clients in relation to ongoing maintenance for previously developed websites

Sep 2006 – Jun 2008 Music Talents Ltd. Web Developer

(Permanent) Enfield, Middlesex

I was responsible for developing, maintaining, and advancing the company's efforts to sell its products on the Internet via its various ecommerce websites. This involved working with a range of technologies such as HTML, CSS, ASP, PHP, MySQL, MS SQL, and WordPress.

- Expanding ecommerce site to add new features, liaising with business manager and company director
- Supporting development towards new websites selling the company products

Mar 2005 – Sep 2006 Sounds Musical Ltd. Junior Web Developer

(Permanent) Waltham Abbey, Essex

Within the IT department of this ecommerce company, my job was to conduct wide-ranging maintenance and testing on the company's ecommerce website.

- Implementing front-end additions/amends for the main ecommerce website (HTML, CSS, ASP)
- Working through reported issues/errors/bugs with the site fix, test and confirm as resolved

EDUCATION

2008 – 2010 <u>King's College London</u>

PgD Advanced Software Engineering

Strand, London

Topics included:

Software Engineering for the Internet, Software Architecture & Design, The Internet Infrastructure Software, Measurement & Testing, Distributed Computing, Access Control Strategy, Artificial Intelligence.

2004 - 2008

London Metropolitan University

BSc (Hons) Computer Visualisation & Games (2:1)

Islington, London

Topics included:

Fundamentals of Computer Science, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures & Algorithms, Database Systems, Software Usability, 2D Computer Graphics, 3D Animation, Game Applications.